<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Death-Sleeps-Here]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/</link><image><url>https://mandruck.github.io/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Death-Sleeps-Here</title><link>https://mandruck.github.io/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 18:57:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mandruck.github.io/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 18:57:35 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This the site for the super cool new award winning ttrpg Dead Sleeps Here. Made by Skyler]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 18:57:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating a Character]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Character Creation typically starts by choosing an Ancestry. This gives you the general physical appearance of your character and a passive ability to represent what the various denizens of the world excel at, and informs you how they are broadly viewed in the world. <br>Next, choose your class. This is the most defining part of how your character fights monsters and interacts with the world. <br>Each class has listed Hit Points, speed, and maximum class resources. Hit points are how many hits your character can dodge or power through before they fall. You start every encounter at that maximum.<br>Speed is how many squares a character can move when they take various move actions.<br>Your maximum class resource is what you spend to use special class abilities that are more powerful than standard actions. You start every encounter at that maximum. <br>A character at level 1 gains the Class Core Skill (if the class has one), then chooses 1 Class Action, 2 Class Resource Actions, and 1 Class Reaction. In addition, you choose a subclass. <br>Taking a subclass grants additional options between your Class Actions, Class Resource Actions, and Class Reactions, but you do not have to take them if your core class has options more to your liking. You will always gain the passive abilities of your subclass. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/0.1-getting-started/creating-a-character.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/0.1 Getting Started/Creating a Character.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 17:31:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Angel]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Angels are the servant's of The Watcher, now long fallen from the heavens and mortal. It is known for Angels to grow wings but only one has kept their second pair of ethereal wings to travel planes and claims to have a way back to the heavens.<br>At level 1, an angel may choose to have one of the following divine aspects:<br>
Seraph: Your angel has a pair of majestic wings that give them flight. You gain a fly speed equal to your move speed.<br>Phoenix: Once when your character dies, they resurrect themselves at maximum HP and Class Resource. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/angel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Angel.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Demi-God]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Demi-Gods are ascended beings, drafted into the armies of one of the gods and bestowed gifts of one of life's aspects. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Paragon of Might: You may hold heavy melee weapons in one hand. <br>Paragon of Agility: Whenever you move, move 1 additional square. <br>Paragon of Intuition<br>Paragon of Intellect<br>Paragon of Presence]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/demi-god.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Demi-God.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Devil]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>Devils are the mortal denizens of the Flame Queen's realm. They excel when their enemies stand at death's door. <br>Blood Hunter: Gain a +1 to attack and damage rolls against bloodied creatures. <br>Night Haunter: When you are adjacent to shadow and take an action that would cause you to move, you may instead teleport an equal distance. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/devil.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Devil.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:33:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dwarf]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Dwarfs are stalwart and hardy beyond all others. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Stone Skin: Your HP increases by 2 at first level and by +1 every level beyond 1st. <br>Thick Skull: Deal double damage to all structures. <br>At level 5 you increase your Damage Resistance by 1. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/dwarf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Dwarf.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 16:27:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elf]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Diviner: At the start of each day roll 2d10 3 times and note the totals. These are your portents. At any point, you may replace any 2d10 roll with one of your portents.<br>Old Soul: Choose a class separate from your own. You gain one of its class resources and one of its class abilities. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/elf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Elf.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Human]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Humans are gifted with burning ambitions and strive to keep up in the dying world around them. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Burning Ambition:  Increase their maximum class resources at level 1.<br>Malleable Mind:  Choose an additional Class Action or Class Resource Action at level 1. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/human.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Human.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Bard]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hit Points: 15<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Inspiration): 4<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light and Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>, light <a data-href="Ranged Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ranged Weapons</a><br><br><br>Core Action<br>
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&nbsp;<br>
Rejuvenation of the Soul: Costs 1 Inspiration. an ally of your choice within 30 feet regains a class resource.&nbsp;<br>
Bard Actions<br><br>Harmonic Blades: Make a basic attack against a target in reach. On a hit, the target takes 2 additional sonic damage from all sources until the start of your next turn. <br>Feint: Make a basic Attack. On a hit, you may choose to deal 0 damage. If you do, you may swap places with a willing ally within 6 squares and roll their damage against the target. <br>Assist: Give all allies within 3 squares a +1d4 bonus on their next attack roll. <br><br>Mock: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 3 squares then cause an enemy within 6 squares to become <a data-href="Annoyed" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/annoyed.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Annoyed</a>.&nbsp;<br>Encourage: Costs 1 Inspiration. Make a basic attack and grant an ally within 6 squares temporary HP equal to your level +Presence. <br>Power Slide: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 3 squares in a straight line that does not provoke attacks of opportunity and allows you to pass through enemy squares. At the end of the movement, you may force an adjacent creature to make a physical saving throw or be pushed 2 squares<br><br>Distract: Costs 1 Inspiration. When you or an ally take damage, you may reduce it by an amount equal to your Presence. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/bard/core-bard.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Bard/Core Bard.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:26:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jester]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lucky: You reroll all natural die rolls of 1<br>Unlucky: When you roll the highest number on a die, you must reroll.<br>Resourceful: When you reroll a die and get the same number, you regain an Inspiration.&nbsp;<br>
Jester Action<br><br>Muse: Roll 4d4.<br>
Jester Inspiration Actions<br><br>Trick of the Light: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 15 feet then swap places with a willing ally within 30 feet.<br>
Jester Reactions<br><br>Wait!: Costs 2 Inspiration: When you are the target of an attack, Roll 1d4. On a 4, the target loses their action.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/bard/jester.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Bard/Jester.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:41:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Blade Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 10/10<br>
Speed: 8 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Blade Arts): 6/6<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Light <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light, Medium, and Heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a> <br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/core-blade-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Core Blade Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 20:56:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flame Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>You automatically pass dexterity saving throws against detonating creatures.&nbsp;<br>
Flame Dancer Actions<br><br>Tracing Flames: as an action, Make a single attack roll and compare it to the creatures in a 3x1 line within reach. Each creature hit takes 1d6 fire damage and is <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a><br>Inescapable Fire: Make a basic attack. The target becomes <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> even on a miss.<br>
Flame Art Actions<br><br>Roaring Flames: Costs 1 Blade Art. Attack a creature within reach. On a hit, deal an additional 1d6 fire damage, if the target is ignited, they also detonate.<br>Scorching Charge:&nbsp; Costs 1 Blade Art. Move 6 squares. This movement allows you to pass through enemies without a check or provoking attacks of opportunity. Make a single basic attack roll and compare it to the AC of all enemies you pass. On a miss, deal half your basic attack damage. <br>Blasting Strike: Costs 1 Blade Art. Make a basic melee attack. On a hit, you may move the target 2 squares. If they are <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> they Detonate after being moved. <br>Rising Fire: Costs 1 Blade Art. Make a basic attack. On a hit, the target flies 3 squares into the air then drops prone. If the target is <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> they Detonate. <br>Wild Fire: Costs 1 Blade Art. Imbue an ally within 6 squares with fire until the end of their next turn. When they damage a creature, it becomes <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a>.<br>
Reactions<br><br>Emboldened Flame: Costs 1 Blade Art. When you are targeted by an attack, make an <a data-href="Interrupt" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/interrupt.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Interrupt</a>attack against the attacking creature. This attack detonates.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/flame-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Flame Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:30:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Cleric]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 20<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Miracles): 3/3<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Heavy <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Shields, Light, and Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a><br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br><br>Lay On Hands: Costs 1 Miracle. As an action, heal a creature adjacent to you for a number of d4s equal to half your level rounded up. Clears all conditions.&nbsp;<br><br>Brand:  Make an attack roll. The target takes 1d6+might damage and suffers -1d4 on their next attack roll against any creature but you.&nbsp;<br>Cleanse:  Touch a creature adjacent to you and clear one condition afflicting them. <br>Divine Lance: Make a ranged attack using intuition in place of might for the attack roll. This attack deals 1d8+intuition radiance damage and on a hit, the target becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>. <br><br>Bring Judgment: Costs 1 Miracle: Make a basic Melee attack. on a hit the target becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a> then takes additional Radiance damage equal to your weapon damage die. <br>Embolden the Soul: Costs 1 Miracle: Move up to your speed. You then gain Temporary HP equal to your Level+Might. All adjacent enemies to you gain <a data-href="Disadvantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/disadvantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Disadvantage</a> on attack rolls on creatures other than you. <br>Wrath of the Gods: Costs 2 Miracles: All enemies within 2 squares must make a saving throw or take Radiance damage equal to your Intuition and be pushed back 2 squares. <br><br>Shield of Gold: Costs 1 miracle: Give an ally within 30 feet 5 damage resistance until the end of your next turn.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/cleric/core-cleric.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Cleric/Core Cleric.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:25:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shield of the Faith]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Laden with Blessings: When you use Lay on Hands, the target increases their Damage Reduction by 2 until the start of your next turn. <br><br>Ward the Faithful: Costs 2 miracles. Grant 5 Temporary HP to all allies within 30 feet.<br>Ward of Dawn: Costs 2 Miracles. Move up to half your speed then create a 3 square radius sphere centered on yourself. Allies within the sphere have their Damage Reduction increased by 1. Creatures can freely pass through the sphere but projectiles are completely blocked. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/cleric/shield-of-the-faith.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Cleric/Shield of the Faith.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 17:29:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Rogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 15/15<br>
Move: 6 squares<br>
Class Resource (Gambits): 5/5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Light <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light, Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a> , and <a data-href="Ranged Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ranged Weapons</a>.<br><br><br><br>When you hit a target while you are hidden they become <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>.<br>
Rogue Actions&nbsp;<br><br> Underhanded Strike: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> then become <a data-href="Hidden" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hidden</a>&nbsp;<br>Fade: Hide until the start of your next turn and move up to your speed.<br>Cloaked Dagger: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> that deals 1d6+agility damage. On a hit the target becomes <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>.<br>
Gambit Actions<br><br>Precision Strike: Costs 1 gambit. When you hit with an attack, deal 1d6 additional weapon damage. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, you instead deal an additional 2d6 weapon damage.&nbsp;This costs no Action. <br>Prediction:&nbsp; Costs 2 Gambits. You may safely move an enemy 4 squares without provoking opportunity attacks.<br>Knock 'em Down: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up to your speed and make a basic attack. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, they become prone.  <br>Disorient: Costs 1 Gambit. Hide and make a basic attack. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, the target becomes <a data-href="Dazed" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/dazed.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Dazed</a>.<br>
Rogue Reactions<br><br>Dodge: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up to half your speed without provoking attacks of opportunity. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/rogue/core-rogue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Rogue/Core Rogue.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:23:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cutthroat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mind for Murder: Add 2 to all damage you deal.<br>
Cutthroat Action<br><br><br>Adrenaline Burst: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up yo half your speed then Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>, if this drops the target to 0 HP, regain an action. <br>Skulk: Costs 2 Gambits. Teleport a number of squares equal to twice your intellect then take a rogue action.<br>
Cutthroat Reactions<br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/rogue/cutthroat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Rogue/Cutthroat.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:17:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Slayer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 20/20<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class resource (Fury): 5/5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Shields, Medium, and Heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>.<br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br><br>Master at Arms: Gain +1 to attack rolls.<br>
Slayer Actions<br><br>Knick: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a miss, deal weapon damage equal to your might.&nbsp;<br>Storm of Iron: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, you may swap places with your target without provoking reactions.&nbsp;<br>Cleave: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. Compare your result to the AC of two targets within reach.<br>Bash: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, push the target back up to two squares.<br><br>Charge: Costs 1 fury. As an action, move up to your speed and make a basic attack.<br>Whirlwind: Costs 2 fury. As an action, make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> and compare it to the AC of every creature adjacent to you. On a miss, deal half your basic attack damage. <br>Over Power: Costs 1 Fury. Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, deal additional damage equal to your weapon die.<br>Pounce: Costs 2 fury. Leap 2 squares high and move a number of squares equal to your might. All adjacent creatures to where you land must succeed a saving throw or be knocked prone.<br>
Reactions&nbsp;<br><br>Parry: costs: 1 fury. When you are hit by an attack, roll the damage of your equipped melee weapon. Reduce the damage you take by the amount rolled. If you reduce the damage to 0, you may apply any remaining damage from your roll to the attacker. If you use this against a group attack, damage is only assigned to the creature that initiated the group attack. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/core-slayer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Core Slayer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:36:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Glory Seeker]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Will to Live: Add your level to all healing you receive. <br>Bloodlust: When you reduce a creature to 0 HP, regain 1 HP.<br>
Glory Seeker Fury Actions<br><br>Reign of Steel: Costs 1 Fury: Make a basic attack against an adjacent target. If you hit, move the target up to 4 squares then follow them.<br>Dethrone: Costs 2 Fury: Make two Slayer Actions.<br>
Glory Seeker Reactions<br><br>Resolve:&nbsp; Costs 1 fury. Heal 2d4. Or If you are suffering an effect a saving throw can end you end it. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/glory-seeker.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Glory Seeker.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:58:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Horde Breaker]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/horde-breaker.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Horde Breaker.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:40:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Vanquisher]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hit Points: 15<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Edicts): 5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, shields, Medium, and heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>,<br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br>Vanquisher Core Passive<br>
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&nbsp;<br><br>Cut Through: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. If this reduces a creature to 0 HP, make a second basic melee attack on a target adjacent to you. <br>Smite the Wicked: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, deal an additional 3 Radiance damage. <br>Dogma: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, the target becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>. <br><br>Decapitation Doctrine: Costs 2 Edicts: Make two <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>s. <br>Empowerment from Above: Costs 1 Edict: Move up to your speed. Until the end of your turn, when you deal damage, you deal additional Radiance damage equal to your Presence. <br>Forward Unto Death: Costs 2 Edicts: You and an ally within 2 squares move up to 4 squares and make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. <br>Emblazon: Costs 1 Edict: Two creatures of your choice within 3 squares become <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>.<br>
Reactions<br><br>Retribution: Costs 1 Edict: After you take damage, use your reaction to deal half the damage you took (Rounded up) to the attacking enemy as Radiance.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/core-vanquisher.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Core Vanquisher.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:43:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Prophet]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Holy Sanctions: You lose all armor and shield proficiencies.<br>Armor of Faith: When you are targeted by an enemy, roll 1d6. On a 1-4, they must select a new target or lose the attack. On a 5 or 6, the attack goes through.<br>
Actions<br><br><br>Words of Faith: Costs 2 Edicts. Grant an ally within 3 squares Armor of Faith. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/prophet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Prophet.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:33:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zealot]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Punishment Due: When a creature damages you, they become <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>.<br><br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/zealot.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Zealot.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:42:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Annoyed]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Annoyed: When an annoyed creature takes damage, they gain Ire.&nbsp;<br>Ire: The creature that damages an annoyed creature becomes the source of their ire. The creature will target the source of their ire on their next turn.&nbsp;]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/annoyed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Annoyed.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 19:28:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dazed]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A dazed creature must spend an additional action to move.&nbsp;]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/dazed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Dazed.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 01:15:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frail]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>While you are frail, taking damage will kill you. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frail.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Frail.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:19:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hidden]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A hidden creature cannot be targeted by attacks and has advantage on attack rolls while hidden. Making an attack loses the hidden condition. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Hidden.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:40:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ignited]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ignited: An ignited creature takes 3 fire damage at the start&nbsp; of their turn. <br>Detonate: When an ignited creature detonates, it and every creature adjacent to it must make a dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 fire damage.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Ignited.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 21:24:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Incandescent]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>An Incandescent creature grants 1d6 hp to a creature that damages it. After being damaged, Incandescent clears. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Incandescent.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 17:34:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Prone]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A prone character is lying flat on the ground. It takes 1 action to stand from prone. Attacks against a prone creature within 5 feet are made at <a data-href="Advantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Advantage</a>. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/prone.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Prone.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:36:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unbalanced]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Unbalanced is a condition that has various detonations, usually from martial classes.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Unbalanced.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:33:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Armor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Armor grants two defenses, Armor Class and Damage Reduction. Armor class is the number an attack roll needs to meet or beat to damage you. Damage Reduction is subtracted from all damage you take.<br>Light Armor: AC: 18<br>Medium Armor: AC: 17 Damage Reduction: 3<br>Heavy Armor: AC: 16: Damage Reduction: 6<br>Shield: A shield will set your armor class to 14 if you are not wearing armor. If you are wearing armor, it will raise your AC by 1. In addition, if you are proficient with shields, you gain the Shield Block reaction.  <br>Shield Block: You may assign damage from an incoming attack to your shield rather than yourself. Your shield has 10 HP and a Hardness of 5. Your shield breaks when it hits 0 HP. When it is broken you cannot Shield Block. If an attack breaks your shield, you take the leftover damage.<br>Hardness reduces incoming damage by the amount next to it. If you were hit for 5 damage and choose to block, your shield will take no damage. If you are hit for 10 damage and choose to block, it will take 5 damage. If you are hit for 15 damage it will take 10 damage and break. If you take 20 damage and choose to block, it will break and you will take 5 damage.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Armor.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:31:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Melee Weapons]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Light weapons deal 1d6 damage and can be held in one hand. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. A light melee weapon can use agility for attack rolls. <br>Precise Light Weapon: Any hit on a prone target is considered a crit.<br>Nimble Light Weapon: Increase your movement speed by 1 square. <br><br>Medium weapons deal 1d8 damage when held in one hand or 1d10 when held with two hands. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. <br>Duelist Medium Weapon: When you take the block reaction, increase your Damage Resistance by an additional 2.<br>Cleaving Medium Weapon: This weapon deals double damage to shields. <br><br>Heavy weapons must be held in both hands and deal 1d12 damage. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. <br>Savage Heavy Weapon: You have <a data-href="Advantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Advantage</a> on damage rolls with this weapon. <br>Crushing Heavy Weapon: When you hit a target with this weapon, you may use your reaction to attempt to knock the target prone. This weapon also deals double damage to structures. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Melee Weapons.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:05:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ranged Weapons]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ranged weapons can reach up to 12 squares and deal 1d6+agility damage. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Ranged Weapons.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:39:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Basic Actions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Basic Actions are a collection of actions all character's have access to, regardless of their class.<br>Move: Move up to your speed.<br>Withdraw: Move 5 feet without provoking attacks of opportunity.<br>Attack: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>.<br>Interact: Use an item, drink a potion, pull a lever, etc.&nbsp;<br>Brace: Gain a +3 bonus to your Damage Reduction until the start of your next turn.&nbsp;<br>Hide: While obscured, you may take the hide action. While <a data-href="Hidden" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hidden</a>, you gain <a data-href="Advantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Advantage</a> on attack rolls against enemies that cannot see you.&nbsp;<br>Shove: Make a contested basic attack roll. If you roll higher you may move a creature adjacent to you 1 square.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/basic-actions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Basic Actions.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:41:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interrupt]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>An Interrupt Action/Reaction resolves before the triggering effect. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/interrupt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Interrupt.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 21:31:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reactions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Every character has one reaction which they can use each turn. The block reaction is always available to every character and costs no resources.<br>Block: Raise your damage reduction by 1 against a single attack. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/reactions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Reactions.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:33:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Basic Attack]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A basic attack is made by rolling 2d10 and adding your Might (or Agility with a light weapon) and then half your level rounded up, plus any relevant modifiers such as from the Slayer's Master at Arms feature or a magic weapon. The formula can be written as such:<br>2d10+Might+Relavent Modifiers. <br>or<br>2d10+Agility+Relavent Modifiers.<br>Some abilities may specify making a basic melee or ranged attack. Those abilities are typically specific to a particular fighting style and must be made with a corresponding weapon. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Basic Attack.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:35:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blaze]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Blaze is a unique ability all characters have access to. In a moment of desperation, your character burns a bit of their soul away to keep pushing forward.<br>Blaze takes no action to use, instead you permanently reduce your class resource by 1. This will not come back after combat ends. When you Blaze, you regain any spent actions, all your HP and rise to your new Class Resource Maximum. <br>Death may not come to you by the sword, but by the burning fires of ambition within yourself. When your class resource maximum becomes 0, you lose your soul. It passes back to the death god's eternal dream, never to be reclaimed. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/blaze.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Blaze.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:54:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Critical Hit]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you roll the same number on each d10 you score a critical hit, also called a crit. A critical hit automatically hits the target, regardless of the total. A Critical Hit also deals Maximum damage. For example,<br>If you crit with a medium weapon which deals 1d8 damage, you would skip the roll and deal 8+might damage. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/critical-hit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Critical Hit.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:22:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dying]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you reach 0 HP you are on the cusp of death. You gain the <a data-href="Frail" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frail.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Frail</a> condition. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/dying.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Dying.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:19:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Initiative]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Initiative is the order in which participants in a combat take turns. Turns are taken in order of highest to lowest. In Death Sleeps Here, initiative is set up to deliberately split the party and be predictable so they can create plans around each other's abilities.<br>Initiative is laid on a numbered track from 1-10. Players have initiative at 8, 7, 4, and 3. Players decide which initiative slot they want at the start of combat.<br><br>A player may swap their initiative with another party member at the start of their turn if both players agree to it. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/initiative.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Initiative.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 15:15:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When combat ends, your character regains all their HP and Class Resources. In addition, they lose all conditions.<br>
2d10 Roll<br><br>Every roll is resolved with 2d10+ability+relevant modifiers.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/the-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/The Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:49:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2d10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Every action is resolved with a 2d10 roll. Roll 2 10 sided dice and add the results together, then add any relevant modifiers. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/2d10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/2d10.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:11:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Advantage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you have advantage on a roll, you roll the die twice and take the higher result.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/Advantage.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:14:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disadvantage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you have disadvantage on a roll, you roll the die twice and take the lower result.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/disadvantage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/Disadvantage.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 19:09:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>