<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Death-Sleeps-Here]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/</link><image><url>https://mandruck.github.io/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Death-Sleeps-Here</title><link>https://mandruck.github.io/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:20:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mandruck.github.io/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:20:14 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Jester]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lucky: You reroll all natural die rolls of 1<br>Unlucky: When you roll the highest number on a die, you must reroll.<br>Resourceful: When you reroll a die and get the same number, you regain an Inspiration.&nbsp;<br><br>Muse: Roll 4d4. <br><br>Trick of the Light: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 3 squares then swap places with a willing ally within 6 squares. Roll 1d4.<br><br>Wait!: Costs 2 Inspiration: When you are the target of an attack, Roll 1d4. On a 3, the target ends their turn.<br>Blind Spot: Costs 1 Inspiration. When you take damage, gain 1 Damage Reduction and teleport to a square adjacent to the creature that damaged you. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/bard/jester.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Bard/Jester.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:14:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Minstrel]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/bard/minstrel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Bard/Minstrel.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:12:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flame Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>You automatically pass dexterity saving throws against detonating creatures.&nbsp;<br><br>Tracing Flames: as an action, Make a single attack roll and compare it to the creatures in a 3x1 line within reach. Each creature hit takes 1d6 fire damage and is <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a><br>Inescapable Fire: Make a basic attack. The target becomes <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> even on a miss.<br><br>Roaring Flames: Costs 1 Blade Art. Attack a creature within reach. On a hit, deal an additional 1d6 fire damage, if the target is ignited, they also detonate.<br>Scorching Charge:&nbsp; Costs 2 Blade Arts. Move 6 squares. This movement allows you to pass through enemies without a check or provoking attacks of opportunity. Make a single basic attack roll and compare it to the AC of all enemies you pass. All enemies that take damage from this attack become <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a>. <br>Blasting Strike: Costs 1 Blade Art. Make a basic melee attack. On a hit, you may move the target 2 squares. If they are <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> they Detonate after being moved. <br>Rising Fire: Costs 1 Blade Art. Make a basic attack. On a hit, the target flies 3 squares into the air then drops prone. If the target is <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> they Detonate after dropping. <br>Wild Fire: Costs 1 Blade Art. Imbue an ally within 6 squares with fire until the end of their next turn. When they damage a creature, it becomes <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a>. <br><br>Emboldened Flame: Costs 1 Blade Art. When you are targeted by an attack, make an <a data-href="Interrupt" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/interrupt.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Interrupt</a>attack against the attacking creature. This attack deals fire damage and detonates <a data-href="Ignited" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ignited</a> creatures.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/flame-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Flame Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:07:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Storm Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/storm-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Storm Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:04:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wave Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/wave-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Wave Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:05:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Resources]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Every class has a specific resource they spend to fuel their special actions. A class resource is only spent on a successful action. Most abilities automatically succeed but some have a chance of failure such as the Jester's Wait! Action. If you were to spend the resource cost and the action fails, you are refunded the spent resources. <br>To use a Class Resource Action, you must have enough resources to use it. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/class-resources.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Class Resources.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:20:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating a Character]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Character Creation typically starts by choosing an Ancestry. This gives you the general physical appearance of your character and a passive ability to represent what the various denizens of the world excel at, and informs you how they are broadly viewed in the world. <br>Next, choose your class. This is the most defining part of how your character fights monsters and interacts with the world. <br>Each class has listed Hit Points, speed, and maximum class resources. Hit points are how many hits your character can dodge or power through before they fall. You start every encounter at that maximum.<br>Speed is how many squares a character can move when they take various move actions.<br>Your maximum class resource is what you spend to use special class abilities that are more powerful than standard actions. You start every encounter at that maximum. <br>A character at level 1 gains the Class Core Skill (if the class has one), then chooses 1 Class Action, 2 Class Resource Actions, and 1 Class Reaction. In addition, you choose a subclass. <br>Taking a subclass grants additional options between your Class Actions, Class Resource Actions, and Class Reactions, but you do not have to take them if your core class has options more to your liking. You will always gain the passive abilities of your subclass and any Core Action they provide.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/0.1-getting-started/creating-a-character.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/0.1 Getting Started/Creating a Character.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:27:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Bard]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hit Points: 15<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Inspiration): 4<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light and Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>, light <a data-href="Ranged Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ranged Weapons</a><br><br><br>Core Action<br>
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&nbsp;<br>
Rejuvenation of the Soul: Costs 1 Inspiration. an ally of your choice within 30 feet regains a class resource.&nbsp;<br>
Bard Actions<br><br>Harmonic Blades: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, the target takes 2 additional sonic damage from all sources until the start of your next turn. <br>Feint: Make a Melee <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, you may choose to deal 0 damage. If you do, you may swap places with a willing ally within 6 squares and use their damage against the target. <br>Assist: Give all allies within 3 squares a +1 bonus on their next attack roll. <br>Quip: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. You may add Presence to the damage in place of Might or Agility.<br>
Inspiration Actions<br><br>Mock: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 3 squares then cause an enemy within 6 squares to become <a data-href="Annoyed" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/annoyed.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Annoyed</a>.&nbsp;<br>Encourage: Costs 1 Inspiration. Make a basic attack and grant an ally within 6 squares temporary HP equal to your level +Presence. <br>Power Slide: Costs 1 Inspiration. Move up to 3 squares in a straight line that does not provoke attacks of opportunity and allows you to pass through enemy squares. At the end of the movement, you may move an adjacent creature to 2 squares<br>Soliloquy: Costs 2 Inspiration. Cause a number of creatures equal to your Presence within 6 squares to become <a data-href="Annoyed" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/annoyed.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Annoyed</a> then choose an ally within 6 squares to deal 1 <a data-href="True Damage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/true-damage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">True Damage</a> to each target.<br>
Reactions<br><br>Distract: Costs 1 Inspiration. When you or an ally take damage, you may reduce it by an amount equal to your Presence. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/bard/core-bard.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Bard/Core Bard.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:31:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shield of the Faith]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Laden with Blessings: When you use Lay on Hands, the target increases their Damage Reduction by 2 until the start of your next turn. <br><br>Challenge: Compel an enemy within 3 squares to move 3 squares closer to you. <br><br>Ward the Faithful: Costs 2 miracles. Grant 5 Temporary HP to all allies within 30 feet.<br>Ward of Dawn: Costs 2 Miracles. Move up to half your speed then create a 3 square radius sphere centered on yourself. Allies within the sphere have their Damage Reduction increased by 1. Creatures can freely pass through the sphere but projectiles are completely blocked. <br><br>Shield of Gold: Costs 1 miracle: Give an ally within 6 squares 5 damage resistance until the start of your next turn.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/cleric/shield-of-the-faith.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Cleric/Shield of the Faith.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:51:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Prophet]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Holy Sanctions: You lose all armor and shield proficiencies.<br>Armor of Faith: When you take damage roll 1d6. On a 1 or 2, the damage goes through. On 3-6 the damage is negated and all effects with it.<br><br><br>Words of Faith: Costs 2 Edicts. Move up to your speed then grant an ally within 3 squares Armor of Faith. <br><br>Mark of Bane: Costs 2 Edicts. Gain 4 damage reduction against an attack that hits you and cause the target to become <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/prophet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Prophet.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:33:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zealot]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Punishment Due: When you reduce a creature to 0 HP you may move up to 3 squares without provoking attacks of Opportunity.<br><br>My Sword is Hatred: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> and cause the target to become <a data-href="Hesitant" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hesitant.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hesitant</a><br>
Zealot Edict Actions<br><br>The Equation to Submission: Costs 1 Edict. move up to your speed then Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. If the Target is <a data-href="Hesitant" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hesitant.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hesitant</a> they become <a data-href="Frightened" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frightened.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Frightened</a>. <br>Pain Plus Time: ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/zealot.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Zealot.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:03:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frightened]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A frightened creature loses 1 action at the start of its turn then loses the frightened condition. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frightened.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Frightened.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:02:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hesitant]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A hesitant creature gains a -1 to their next power roll]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hesitant.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Hesitant.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[True Damage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>True Damage cannot be reduced in any way. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/true-damage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/True Damage.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:30:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Cleric]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 20<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Miracles): 3/3<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Heavy <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Shields, Light, and Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a><br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br><br>Lay On Hands: Costs 1 Miracle. As an action, heal a creature adjacent to you for a number of d4s equal to half your level rounded up. Clears all conditions.&nbsp;<br><br>Brand:  Make an attack roll. The target takes 1d6+might damage and suffers -1d4 on their next attack roll against any creature but you.&nbsp;<br>Cleanse:  Touch a creature adjacent to you and clear one condition afflicting them. <br>Divine Lance: Make ranged attack with a range of 8 squares. This attack adds your Intuition to the damage and deals Radiance. the target also becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>. <br>Divine Lance Power Matrix:<br><br><br>Bring Judgment: Costs 1 Miracle: Make a basic Melee attack. on a hit the target becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a> then takes additional Radiance damage equal to your weapon damage die. <br>Embolden the Soul: Costs 1 Miracle: Move up to your speed. You then gain Temporary HP equal to your Level+Might. All adjacent enemies to you gain <a data-href="Disadvantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/disadvantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Disadvantage</a> on attack rolls on creatures other than you. <br>Wrath of the Gods: Costs 2 Miracles: All enemies within 2 squares take Radiance damage equal to your Intuition and are pushed back 2 squares. <br><br>The Righteous Deliverance of Retribution: Costs 2 Miracles. When an ally you can see is harmed, you Smite the creature that dared harm them. You then gain a pool of healing equal to the damage dealt to distribute amongst your allies within 6 squares. <br>Smite Power Matrix: <br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/cleric/core-cleric.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Cleric/Core Cleric.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:21:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Slayer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 20/20<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class resource (Fury): 5/5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Shields, Medium, and Heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>.<br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br><br>Master at Arms: Gain +1 to attack rolls.<br><br>Knick: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. Any roll on the Power Matrix below 8 is considered 8.&nbsp;<br>Storm of Iron: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, you may swap places with your target without provoking reactions.&nbsp;<br>Cleave: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. Compare your result to the AC of two targets within reach.<br>Bash: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, push the target back up to two squares.<br><br>Charge: Costs 1 fury. As an action, move up to your speed and make a basic attack.<br>Whirlwind: Costs 2 fury. As an action, make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> and compare it to the AC of every creature adjacent to you. <br>Over Power: Costs 1 Fury. Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. On a hit, deal additional damage equal to your Might.<br>Pounce: Costs 2 fury. Leap 2 squares high and move a number of squares equal to your might. All adjacent creatures to where you land are knocked prone.<br><br>Parry: costs: 1 fury. When you are hit by an attack, roll the damage of your equipped melee weapon. Reduce the damage you take by the amount rolled. If you reduce the damage to 0, you may apply any remaining damage from your roll to the attacker. If you use this against a group attack, damage is only assigned to the creature that initiated the group attack. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/core-slayer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Core Slayer.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:30:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Armor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Most armor gives a character Damage Reduction, subtracting its value from each instance of damage they take. Light armor instead gives a a unique defense known as Damage threshold.<br>A Damage Threshold is a value that must be met before a character takes any damage. If the threshold is met or exceeded, the character takes all damage from the attack. <br>Agile Armor: Damage Threshold: 8<br>Medium Armor: Damage Reduction: 4<br>Heavy Armor: Damage Reduction: 6<br>Shield: A shield will set your DR to 4 if you are not wearing armor. If you are wearing armor, it will raise your DR by 1. In addition, if you are proficient with shields, you gain the Shield Block reaction.  <br>Shield Block: A shield has 3 HP. Each time you use the Shield Block reaction, it lowers its HP by 1. When you Shield Block, you lower an incoming attack to the lowest tier of its Power Matrix. When a shield is dropped to 0 HP it breaks and must be replaced. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Armor.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:05:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Equipping Equipment]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A character can only wear 1 suit of armor.<br><br>A character can wield up to 2 weapons. Holding 2 weapons is known as dual wielding. While a character is dual wielding the same weapon type they gain a +1 to the Power Matrix roll. If they are dual wielding 2 different weapons they benefit from both weapon's abilities but must specify which weapon they are attacking with before making a Power Matrix roll. <br><br>Your character only benefits from the weapon ability of a weapon they are currently wielding. If it is stowed or not on your person, they gain no benefit. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/equipping-equipment.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Equipping Equipment.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:23:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Melee Weapons]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Light weapons can be held in one hand. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. A light melee weapon can use agility for damage. <br>Precise Light Weapon: Ignore 2 points of Damage Reduction. <br>Nimble Light Weapon: Increase your movement speed by 1 square. <br>Light Weapon Power Matrix:<br><br><br>Medium weapons have 2 outcomes on the Power Matrix, the first is when wielding it in 1 hand, the second is when wielding it in 2 hands. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. <br>Duelist Medium Weapon: When you take the block reaction, increase your Damage Resistance by an additional 2.<br>Cleaving Medium Weapon: This weapon deals double damage to shields. <br>Medium Weapon Power Matrix:<br><br><br>Heavy weapons must be held in both hands and deal 1d12 damage. Its type can be slashing, piercing or blunt. <br>Savage Heavy Weapon: (WiP). <br>Inescapable Heavy Weapon: This weapon has a reach of 2 squares. <br>Crushing Heavy Weapon: When you hit a target with this weapon, you may use your reaction to attempt to knock the target prone. This weapon also deals double damage to structures. <br>Heavy Weapon Power Matrix:<br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Melee Weapons.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:12:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ranged Weapons]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ranged weapons can reach up to 12 squares. Making an attack with a ranged weapon while adjacent to a hostile imposes <a data-href="Disadvantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/disadvantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Disadvantage</a> on the attack. In addition, Agility is added to their damage in place of Might. <br><br>Reliable: Ignores 1 DR<br>Swift: Increase your speed by 1.<br><br><br>Titan String: Add Might to damage in place of Agility. <br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Equipment/Ranged Weapons.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:23:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dying]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>While you are at 0 HP you are on the cusp of death. While at 0 HP you have the <a data-href="Frail" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frail.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Frail</a> condition. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/dying.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Dying.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:29:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Glory Seeker]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Will to Live: Add your level to all healing you receive. <br>Bloodlust: When you reduce a creature to 0 HP, regain 1 HP.<br>
Glory Seeker Fury Actions<br><br>Reign of Steel: Costs 1 Fury: Make a basic attack against an adjacent target. If you hit, move the target up to 4 squares then follow them without provoking Attacks of Opportunity.<br>Dethrone: Costs 2 Fury: Make two Slayer Actions.<br>
Glory Seeker Reactions<br><br>Resolve:&nbsp; Costs 1 fury. When you are afflicted with a condition or take damage you may Heal 2d4 HP or clear all conditions afflicting you.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/glory-seeker.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Glory Seeker.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 02:06:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Doom]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A creature inflicted with Doom takes 3 additional damage from all sources.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/doom.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Doom.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 03:28:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Necrosis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A creature suffering Necrosis lowers their DR by 1. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/necrosis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Necrosis.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 02:01:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Blade Dancer]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 10/10<br>
Speed: 8 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Blade Arts): 6/6<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Light <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light, Medium, and Heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a> <br><br><br><br>Dance of Steel: You may make attack rolls using agility instead of might with all weapons. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/blade-dancer/core-blade-dancer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Blade Dancer/Core Blade Dancer.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 23:43:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Vanquisher]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hit Points: 15<br>
Speed: 6 Squares<br>
Class Resource (Edicts): 5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Medium <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, shields, Medium, and heavy <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a>,<br>
Ability Scores  <br><br><br>Vanquisher Core Passive<br>
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&nbsp;<br><br>Cut Through: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. If this reduces a creature to 0 HP, make a second basic melee attack on a target adjacent to you. <br>Smite the Wicked: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. Deal an additional 3 Radiance damage. <br>Dogma: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. The target becomes <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>. <br><br>Decapitation Doctrine: Costs 2 Edicts: Make two <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>s. <br>Empowerment from Above: Costs 1 Edict: Move up to your speed. Until the end of your turn, when you deal damage, you deal additional Radiance damage equal to your Presence. <br>Forward Unto Death: Costs 2 Edicts: You and an ally within 2 squares move up to 4 squares and make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>. <br>Emblazon: Costs 1 Edict: Move up to 3 squares then 2 creatures of your choice within 3 squares become <a data-href="Incandescent" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Incandescent</a>.  <br><br>Retribution: Costs 1 Edict: After you take damage, use your reaction to deal half the damage you took (Rounded up) to the attacking enemy as Radiance.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/vanquisher/core-vanquisher.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Vanquisher/Core Vanquisher.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 01:18:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Basic Attack]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A basic attack is made by rolling 2d10 and adding any relevant modifiers such as the Salyer's Master at Arms ability. Compare the roll to your <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a> or <a data-href="Ranged Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ranged Weapons</a> Power Matrix and deal the corresponding damage + relevant stat. Normally this is Might, but this can be changed by some abilities. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Basic Attack.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Critical Hit]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you roll the same number on each d10 you score a critical hit, also called a crit.<br>
When you roll a crit, you may immediately take an additional action or gain a class resource. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/critical-hit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Critical Hit.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:46:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Rogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>HP: 15/15<br>
Move: 6 squares<br>
Class Resource (Gambits): 5/5<br>
Equipment Proficiencies: Light <a data-href="Armor" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/armor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Armor</a>, Light, Medium <a data-href="Melee Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/melee-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Melee Weapons</a> , and <a data-href="Ranged Weapons" href="https://mandruck.github.io/equipment/ranged-weapons.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ranged Weapons</a>.<br><br><br><br>When you hit a target while you are hidden they become <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>.<br><br> Underhanded Strike: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> then become <a data-href="Hidden" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hidden</a>&nbsp;<br>Fade: Hide until the start of your next turn and move up to your speed.<br>Cloaked Dagger: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a> that deals 1d6+agility damage. On a hit the target becomes <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>. <br><br>Precision Strike: Costs 1 gambit. When you hit with an attack, deal 1d6 additional weapon damage. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, you instead deal an additional 2d6 weapon damage.&nbsp;This costs no Action. <br>Prediction:&nbsp; Costs 2 Gambits. You may safely move an enemy 4 squares without provoking opportunity attacks.<br>Knock 'em Down: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up to your speed and make a basic attack. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, they become prone.  <br>Disorient: Costs 1 Gambit. Hide and make a basic attack. If the target is <a data-href="Unbalanced" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unbalanced</a>, the target becomes <a data-href="Dazed" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/dazed.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Dazed</a>. <br><br>Dodge: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up to half your speed without provoking attacks of opportunity. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/rogue/core-rogue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Rogue/Core Rogue.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 02:14:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cutthroat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mind for Murder: Add 2 to all damage you deal. <br><br><br>Adrenaline Burst: Costs 1 Gambit. Move up yo half your speed then Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>, if this drops the target to 0 HP, regain an action. <br>Skulk: Costs 2 Gambits. Teleport a number of squares equal to twice your intellect then take a rogue action. <br>]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/rogue/cutthroat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Rogue/Cutthroat.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 02:14:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fall Damage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>If you willingly jump from a ledge, you take 1d6 bludgeoning damage for every square beyond your agility. If you are unwillingly moved over a ledge or thrown high into the air you take 1d6 bludgeoning damage for every square you fall. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/fall-damage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Fall Damage.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 01:59:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A Required ingredient of internet soup.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 02:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Angel]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Angels are the servant's of The Watcher, now long fallen from the heavens and mortal. It is known for Angels to grow wings but only one has kept their second pair of ethereal wings to travel planes and claims to have a way back to the heavens.<br>At level 1, an angel may choose to have one of the following divine aspects:<br>
Seraph: Your angel has a pair of majestic wings that give them flight. You gain a fly speed equal to your move speed.<br>Phoenix: Once when your character dies, they resurrect themselves at maximum HP and Class Resource. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/angel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Angel.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Demi-God]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Demi-Gods are ascended beings, drafted into the armies of one of the gods and bestowed gifts of one of life's aspects. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Paragon of Might: You may hold heavy melee weapons in one hand. <br>Paragon of Agility: Whenever you move, move 1 additional square. <br>Paragon of Intuition<br>Paragon of Intellect<br>Paragon of Presence]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/demi-god.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Demi-God.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Devil]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>Devils are the mortal denizens of the Flame Queen's realm. They excel when their enemies stand at death's door. <br>Blood Hunter: Gain a +1 to attack and damage rolls against bloodied creatures. <br>Night Haunter: When you are adjacent to shadow and take an action that would cause you to move, you may instead teleport an equal distance. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/devil.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Devil.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:33:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dwarf]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Dwarfs are stalwart and hardy beyond all others. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Stone Skin: Your HP increases by 2 at first level and by +1 every level beyond 1st. <br>Thick Skull: Deal double damage to all structures. <br>At level 5 you increase your Damage Resistance by 1. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/dwarf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Dwarf.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 16:27:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elf]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Diviner: At the start of each day roll 2d10 3 times and note the totals. These are your portents. At any point, you may replace any 2d10 roll with one of your portents.<br>Old Soul: Choose a class separate from your own. You gain one of its class resources and one of its class abilities. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/elf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Elf.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Human]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Humans are gifted with burning ambitions and strive to keep up in the dying world around them. <br>Choose one of the following abilities at level 1.<br>
Burning Ambition:  Increase their maximum class resources at level 1.<br>Malleable Mind:  Choose an additional Class Action or Class Resource Action at level 1. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/ancestry/human.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Ancestry/Human.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:34:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Horde Breaker]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/character-creation/classes/slayer/horde-breaker.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Creation/Classes/Slayer/Horde Breaker.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:40:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Annoyed]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Annoyed: When an annoyed creature takes damage, they gain Ire.&nbsp;<br>Ire: The creature that damages an annoyed creature becomes the source of their ire. The creature will target the source of their ire on their next turn.&nbsp;]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/annoyed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Annoyed.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 19:28:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dazed]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A dazed creature must spend an additional action to move.&nbsp;]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/dazed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Dazed.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 01:15:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frail]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>While you are frail, taking damage will kill you. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/frail.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Frail.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:19:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hidden]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A hidden creature cannot be targeted by attacks and has advantage on attack rolls while hidden. Making an attack loses the hidden condition. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Hidden.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:40:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ignited]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ignited: An ignited creature takes 3 fire damage at the start&nbsp; of their turn. <br>Detonate: When an ignited creature detonates, it and every creature adjacent to it must make a dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 fire damage.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/ignited.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Ignited.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 21:24:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Incandescent]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>An Incandescent creature grants 1d6 hp to a creature that damages it. After being damaged, Incandescent clears. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/incandescent.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Incandescent.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 17:34:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Prone]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A prone character is lying flat on the ground. It takes 1 action to stand from prone. Attacks against a prone creature within 5 feet are made at <a data-href="Advantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Advantage</a>. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/prone.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Prone.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:36:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unbalanced]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Unbalanced is a condition that has various detonations, usually from martial classes.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/unbalanced.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditions/Unbalanced.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 16:33:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Basic Actions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Basic Actions are a collection of actions all character's have access to, regardless of their class.<br>Move: Move up to your speed.<br>Withdraw: Move 5 feet without provoking attacks of opportunity.<br>Attack: Make a <a data-href="Basic Attack" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/basic-attack.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Basic Attack</a>.<br>Interact: Use an item, drink a potion, pull a lever, etc.&nbsp;<br>Brace: Gain a +3 bonus to your Damage Reduction until the start of your next turn.&nbsp;<br>Hide: While obscured, you may take the hide action. While <a data-href="Hidden" href="https://mandruck.github.io/conditions/hidden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hidden</a>, you gain <a data-href="Advantage" href="https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Advantage</a> on attack rolls against enemies that cannot see you.&nbsp;<br>Shove: Make a contested basic attack roll. If you roll higher you may move a creature adjacent to you 1 square.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/basic-actions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Basic Actions.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:41:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interrupt]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>An Interrupt Action/Reaction resolves before the triggering effect. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/interrupt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Interrupt.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 21:31:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reactions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Every character has one reaction which they can use each turn. The block reaction is always available to every character and costs no resources.<br>Block: Raise your damage reduction by 1 against a single attack. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/actions/reactions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Actions/Reactions.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:33:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blaze]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Blaze is a unique ability all characters have access to. In a moment of desperation, your character burns a bit of their soul away to keep pushing forward.<br>Blaze takes no action to use, instead you permanently reduce your class resource by 1. This will not come back after combat ends. When you Blaze, you regain any spent actions, all your HP and rise to your new Class Resource Maximum. <br>Death may not come to you by the sword, but by the burning fires of ambition within yourself. When your class resource maximum becomes 0, you lose your soul. It passes back to the death god's eternal dream, never to be reclaimed. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/blaze.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Blaze.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:54:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Initiative]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Initiative is the order in which participants in a combat take turns. Turns are taken in order of highest to lowest. In Death Sleeps Here, initiative is set up to deliberately split the party and be predictable so they can create plans around each other's abilities.<br>Initiative is laid on a numbered track from 1-10. Players have initiative at 8, 7, 4, and 3. Players decide which initiative slot they want at the start of combat.<br><br>A player may swap their initiative with another party member at the start of their turn if both players agree to it. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/initiative.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/Initiative.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 15:15:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When combat ends, your character regains all their HP and Class Resources. In addition, they lose all conditions.<br>
2d10 Roll<br><br>Every roll is resolved with 2d10+ability+relevant modifiers.]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/combat/the-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/Combat/The Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:49:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2d10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Every action is resolved with a 2d10 roll. Roll 2 10 sided dice and add the results together, then add any relevant modifiers. ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/2d10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/2d10.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 14:11:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Advantage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you have advantage on a roll, you roll the die twice and take the higher result.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/advantage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/Advantage.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:14:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disadvantage]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>When you have disadvantage on a roll, you roll the die twice and take the lower result.  ]]></description><link>https://mandruck.github.io/rules/the-dice/disadvantage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Rules/The Dice/Disadvantage.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 19:09:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>